<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Yu Feng 冯煜</title>
    <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr. Yu Feng 冯煜</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yuzzfeng.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting core forms of urban morphology linked to urban functions with explainable graph neural network</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2025_ceus_chen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2025_ceus_chen/</guid>
      <description>Chen, D., Feng, Y., Li, X., Qu, M., Luo, P., &amp;amp; Meng, L. (2025). Interpreting core forms of urban morphology linked to urban functions with explainable graph neural network. Computers, Environment and Urban Systems, 118, 102267.
Abstract Understanding the high-order relationship between urban form and function is essential for modeling the underlying mechanisms of sustainable urban systems. Nevertheless, it is challenging to establish an accurate data representation for complex urban forms that are readily explicable in human terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎯 Funding received from NFDI4Earth collaborating with the archives of the Bavarian State (GDA)</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2025_n4e_incubator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2025_n4e_incubator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PhenoMapping: A participatory visual tool for curation and verification of historical phenological data&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a Lecturer / Postdoctoral Researcher in Geoinformatics and Cartography at the Technical University of Munich (TUM) Chair of Cartography and Visual Analytics since 2022, under the lead of Prof. Dr.-Ing. Liqiu Meng. Previously, I worked as a research associate at the Institute of Cartography and Geoinformatics (ikg), Leibniz University Hannover, and finished my PhD with distinction (summa cum laude) in 2021 under the supervision of Prof. Dr.-Ing. habil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎯 Funding received from DAAD PPP in collaboration with the University of Glasgow</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_daad_ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_daad_ppp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A real-world data-driven simulator for interaction-aware autonomous driving benchmarking&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking in the Shade: Shadow-oriented Navigation for Pedestrians</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2024_acm_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2024_acm_feng/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Zhang, P., Xue, J., Chen, Z., &amp;amp; Meng, L. (2024, October). Walking in the Shade: Shadow-oriented Navigation for Pedestrians. In Proceedings of the 32nd ACM International Conference on Advances in Geographic Information Systems (pp. 677-680).
Abstract Excessive exposure to the sun and the resulting heat poses health risks to pedestrians in hot weather. To mitigate these risks, we propose a shadow-oriented navigation system that offers cooler and more convenient walking routes by simulating shadows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📖 Journal paper accepted by CaGIS</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_cagis_wang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_cagis_wang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mixed reality-based coordinate system for enhancing survey knowledge acquisition: a study on allocentric and egocentric perspectives [&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/15230406.2024.2409915&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2024_isprs_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2024_isprs_feng/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Xu, Y., Xia, Y., Brenner, C., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2024). Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 215, 331-350.
Abstract Recent advances in mobile mapping systems have greatly enhanced the efficiency and convenience of acquiring urban 3D data. These systems utilize LiDAR sensors mounted on vehicles to capture vast cityscapes. However, a significant challenge arises due to occlusions caused by roadside parked vehicles, leading to the loss of scene information, particularly on the roads, sidewalks, curbs, and the lower sections of buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📖 Journal paper accepted by ISPRS J. P&amp;RS</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_isprs_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_isprs_feng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net [&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2024.07.009&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BeBaOI: Benchmark and Baseline Methods for determining Overlapping Images, 02.2023 - 01.2024 (finished project)</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/projects/2024_si_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/projects/2024_si_feng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PI, funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.isprs.org/society/si/SI-2023/default.aspx&#34;&gt;ISPRS Scientific Initiatives&lt;/a&gt; and collaborated with Assistant Professor, &lt;a href=&#34;https://xwangsgg.github.io/&#34;&gt;Dr.-Ing. Xin Wang&lt;/a&gt;, School of Geodesy and Geomatics, Wuhan University. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.isprs.org/society/si/SI-2023/TC21_Application_(Xin_Wang)_Report.pdf&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge discovery and visual analysis for urban mobility data in Munich and Helsinki, 02.2023 - 01.2024 (finished project)</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/projects/2024_gif_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/projects/2024_gif_feng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;co-PI, funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.international.tum.de/en/global/gif/&#34;&gt;TUM Global Incentive Fund&lt;/a&gt; and collaborated with Assistant Professor, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gistlab.science/rushmore_teams/henrikki-tenkanen/&#34;&gt;Dr. Henrikki Tenkanen&lt;/a&gt;, Department of Built Environment, Aalto University.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraction and analysis of natural disaster-related VGI from social media: review, opportunities and challenges</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2022_ijgis_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2022_ijgis_feng/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Huang, X., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2022). Extraction and analysis of natural disaster-related VGI from social media: review, opportunities and challenges. International Journal of Geographical Information Science, 36(7), 1275-1316.
Abstract The idea of ‘citizen as sensors’ has gradually become a reality over the past decade. Today, Volunteered Geographic Information (VGI) from citizens is highly involved in acquiring information on natural disasters. In particular, the rapid development of deep learning techniques in computer vision and natural language processing in recent years has allowed more information related to natural disasters to be extracted from social media, such as the severity of building damage and flood water levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determination of building flood risk maps from LiDAR mobile mapping data</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2022_ceus_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2022_ceus_feng/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Xiao, Q., Brenner, C., Peche, A., Yang, J., Feuerhake, U., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2022). Determination of building flood risk maps from LiDAR mobile mapping data. Computers, Environment and Urban Systems, 93, 101759.
Abstract With increasing urbanization, flooding is a major challenge for many cities today. Based on forecast precipitation, topography, and pipe networks, flood simulations can provide early warnings for areas and buildings at risk of flooding. Basement windows, doors, and underground garage entrances are common places where floodwater can flow into a building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flood severity mapping from Volunteered Geographic Information by interpreting water level from images containing people: A case study of Hurricane Harvey</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2020_isprs_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2020_isprs_feng/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Xu, Y., Xia, Y., Brenner, C., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2024). Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 215, 331-350.
Abstract With increasing urbanization, in recent years there has been a growing interest and need in monitoring and analyzing urban flood events. Social media, as a new data source, can provide real-time information for flood monitoring. The social media posts with locations are often referred to as Volunteered Geographic Information (VGI), which can reveal the spatial pattern of such events.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
