<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Yu Feng 冯煜</title>
    <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr. Yu Feng 冯煜</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yuzzfeng.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a Lecturer / Postdoctoral Researcher in Geoinformatics and Cartography at the Technical University of Munich (TUM) Chair of Cartography and Visual Analytics since 2022, under the lead of Prof. Dr.-Ing. Liqiu Meng. Previously, I worked as a research associate at the Institute of Cartography and Geoinformatics (ikg), Leibniz University Hannover, and finished my PhD with distinction (summa cum laude) in 2021 under the supervision of Prof. Dr.-Ing. habil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎯 Funding received from DAAD PPP in collaboration with the University of Glasgow</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_daad_ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_daad_ppp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A real-world data-driven simulator for interaction-aware autonomous driving benchmarking&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📖 Journal paper accepted by CaGIS</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_cagis_wang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_cagis_wang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mixed reality-based coordinate system for enhancing survey knowledge acquisition: a study on allocentric and egocentric perspectives [&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/15230406.2024.2409915&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2024_isprs_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2024_isprs_feng/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Xu, Y., Xia, Y., Brenner, C., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2024). Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 215, 331-350.
Abstract Recent advances in mobile mapping systems have greatly enhanced the efficiency and convenience of acquiring urban 3D data. These systems utilize LiDAR sensors mounted on vehicles to capture vast cityscapes. However, a significant challenge arises due to occlusions caused by roadside parked vehicles, leading to the loss of scene information, particularly on the roads, sidewalks, curbs, and the lower sections of buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📖 Journal paper accepted by ISPRS J. P&amp;RS</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_isprs_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/news/2024_isprs_feng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net [&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2024.07.009&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BeBaOI: Benchmark and Baseline Methods for determining Overlapping Images, 02.2023 - 01.2024 (finished project)</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/projects/2024_si_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/projects/2024_si_feng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PI, funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.isprs.org/society/si/SI-2023/default.aspx&#34;&gt;ISPRS Scientific Initiatives&lt;/a&gt; and collaborated with Assistant Professor, &lt;a href=&#34;https://xwangsgg.github.io/&#34;&gt;Dr.-Ing. Xin Wang&lt;/a&gt;, School of Geodesy and Geomatics, Wuhan University. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.isprs.org/society/si/SI-2023/TC21_Application_(Xin_Wang)_Report.pdf&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge discovery and visual analysis for urban mobility data in Munich and Helsinki, 02.2023 - 01.2024 (finished project)</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/projects/2024_gif_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/projects/2024_gif_feng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;co-PI, funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.international.tum.de/en/global/gif/&#34;&gt;TUM Global Incentive Fund&lt;/a&gt; and collaborated with Assistant Professor, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gistlab.science/rushmore_teams/henrikki-tenkanen/&#34;&gt;Dr. Henrikki Tenkanen&lt;/a&gt;, Department of Built Environment, Aalto University.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flood severity mapping from Volunteered Geographic Information by interpreting water level from images containing people: A case study of Hurricane Harvey</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2020_isprs_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2020_isprs_feng/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Xu, Y., Xia, Y., Brenner, C., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2024). Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 215, 331-350.
Abstract With increasing urbanization, in recent years there has been a growing interest and need in monitoring and analyzing urban flood events. Social media, as a new data source, can provide real-time information for flood monitoring. The social media posts with locations are often referred to as Volunteered Geographic Information (VGI), which can reveal the spatial pattern of such events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arizona, US</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/arizona-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/arizona-us/</guid>
      <description>The Grand Canyon is a steep-sided canyon carved by the Colorado River in Arizona, United States. The canyon is 277 miles (446 km) long, up to 18 miles (29 km) wide and attains a depth of over a mile (6,093 feet or 1,857 meters).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
