<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Yu Feng</title>
    <link>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr. Yu Feng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Funding received from DAAD PPP with University of Glasgow</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/news/2024_daad_ppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/news/2024_daad_ppp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A real-world data-driven simulator for interaction-aware autonomous driving benchmarking, funded by DAAD Programmes for Project-Related Personal Exchange (PPP) with Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal paper accepted by CaGIS</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/news/2024_cagis_wang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/news/2024_cagis_wang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wang, S., Liu, B., Feng, Y., &amp;amp; Meng, L. (2024). Mixed reality-based coordinate system for enhancing survey knowledge acquisition: a study on allocentric and egocentric perspectives. Cartography and Geographic Information Science, 1-21.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/publications/2024_isprs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/publications/2024_isprs/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Xu, Y., Xia, Y., Brenner, C., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2024). Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 215, 331-350.
Abstract Recent advances in mobile mapping systems have greatly enhanced the efficiency and convenience of acquiring urban 3D data. These systems utilize LiDAR sensors mounted on vehicles to capture vast cityscapes. However, a significant challenge arises due to occlusions caused by roadside parked vehicles, leading to the loss of scene information, particularly on the roads, sidewalks, curbs, and the lower sections of buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal paper accepted by ISPRS J. of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/news/2024_isprs_feng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/news/2024_isprs_feng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feng, Y., Xu, Y., Xia, Y., Brenner, C., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2024). Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 215, 331-350.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flood severity mapping from Volunteered Geographic Information by interpreting water level from images containing people: A case study of Hurricane Harvey</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/publications/2020_isprs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/publications/2020_isprs/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Xu, Y., Xia, Y., Brenner, C., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2024). Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 215, 331-350.
Abstract With increasing urbanization, in recent years there has been a growing interest and need in monitoring and analyzing urban flood events. Social media, as a new data source, can provide real-time information for flood monitoring. The social media posts with locations are often referred to as Volunteered Geographic Information (VGI), which can reveal the spatial pattern of such events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arizona, US</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/publications/arizona-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/publications/arizona-us/</guid>
      <description>The Grand Canyon is a steep-sided canyon carved by the Colorado River in Arizona, United States. The canyon is 277 miles (446 km) long, up to 18 miles (29 km) wide and attains a depth of over a mile (6,093 feet or 1,857 meters).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a Lecturer / Postdoctoral Researcher in Geoinformatics and Cartography at the Technical University of Munich (TUM) since 2022. Previously, I worked as a research associate at the Institute of Cartography and Geoinformatics (ikg), Leibniz University Hannover, and finished my PhD with distinction in 2021.
My research interests include:
 Geospatial artificial intelligence (GeoAI) and question answering Volunteered Geographic Information (VGI) - social media for disaster monitoring Cartographic Generalization with deep learning methods Mobile Laser Scanning (MLS) data processing and modeling  Copyright © 2024 Yu Feng</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
