<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publication on Dr. Yu Feng</title>
    <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publication on Dr. Yu Feng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2024_isprs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2024_isprs/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Xu, Y., Xia, Y., Brenner, C., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2024). Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 215, 331-350.
Abstract Recent advances in mobile mapping systems have greatly enhanced the efficiency and convenience of acquiring urban 3D data. These systems utilize LiDAR sensors mounted on vehicles to capture vast cityscapes. However, a significant challenge arises due to occlusions caused by roadside parked vehicles, leading to the loss of scene information, particularly on the roads, sidewalks, curbs, and the lower sections of buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flood severity mapping from Volunteered Geographic Information by interpreting water level from images containing people: A case study of Hurricane Harvey</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2020_isprs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/2020_isprs/</guid>
      <description>Feng, Y., Xu, Y., Xia, Y., Brenner, C., &amp;amp; Sester, M. (2024). Gap completion in point cloud scene occluded by vehicles using SGC-Net. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 215, 331-350.
Abstract With increasing urbanization, in recent years there has been a growing interest and need in monitoring and analyzing urban flood events. Social media, as a new data source, can provide real-time information for flood monitoring. The social media posts with locations are often referred to as Volunteered Geographic Information (VGI), which can reveal the spatial pattern of such events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arizona, US</title>
      <link>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/arizona-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuzzfeng.github.io/publications/arizona-us/</guid>
      <description>The Grand Canyon is a steep-sided canyon carved by the Colorado River in Arizona, United States. The canyon is 277 miles (446 km) long, up to 18 miles (29 km) wide and attains a depth of over a mile (6,093 feet or 1,857 meters).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
